JACOB JONES

WEB DEVELOPER

■ mrjacobtaiwan@gmail.com www.jacobmjones.com 647 649-8747
in /jacob-jones-139750168/ JacobMJones

SUMMARY

Full stack developer and React lover with ten years of experience working in education and three years in network and desktop support. I have always had a passion for computers, using them to create art, music and games, and as an adjunct in my former job as an educator. My experience using technology in video game design, education, and now web development makes me a good addition to a development team. I am a fast learner with a passion for programming.

SKILLS

DATABASES: MongoDB, Firebase

LIBRARIES: React, jQuery, styled-components

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, C#, Ruby

OTHER: Unity3d, Blender, Photoshop, Invision

PROJECTS

Kids Help Phone Intake System

Express, React. I participated in GiftTheCode, a charitable hackathon that paired teams of developers with different charities. My team submitted a winning entry, a child-centred intake system. Our backend was a simple express server connecting the intake system to a queue management system that monitored the children's answers in real time. The intake system used templates to allow for the rapid creation of playful question pages.

Review Radar June 2018

Express, React. Review Radar combines scraping tools (Cheerio and Puppeteer) with machine learning APIs (Watson and Meaning Cloud) to aggregate and enhance customer reviews for businesses. While learning to scrape and use machine learning APIs was very interesting, my favourite part of this project was deciding how to structure and process our data.

The Light Machine

Aug. 2017 - Oct. 2017

Dec. 2018

C#, Unity, Photoshop, and Blender. While first and foremost a labor of love, this game was a way to learn about state machines, raycasting, 3D modelling, and various game design patterns. In creating this game I greatly expanded my knowledge of C# and OOP. What's more, it showed me the tremendous amount of work that is involved in creating a proper video game. Building this game was a way of discovering if I wanted to become a professional programmer.

English Phonics Trainer

Apr. 2017 - Current

Unity, C#. The English Phonics Trainer was designed for both young students learning English phonics and also for parents, who spoke little to no English, to enable them to help their children at home. It was designed for Android phones. The greatest challenge of this project was the QA process, specifically getting the application to look good on various phone sizes.

EMPLOYMENT

Phyxable, React Developer, Toronto, Canada

Aug. 2018 - Feb. 2019

- Worked with a UX researcher and a UI designer prototyping MVPs for user testing
- Built a Headspace style app to deliver the company's video content
- Created an authentication system with protected routes using React-Router and Firebase
- Managed state using React's Context API
- Procedurally generated rehab sessions for users from a data object
- Created a user dashboard that reflected user progress and rights
- Created and maintained a noSQL database on Firebase
- Deployed cloud functions for credit card processing, authentication, and tracking user progress
- Created and maintained a standard corporate landing page
- Deployed a successful SEO strategy for an SPA, working with meta tags, pre-rendering, schema tags, and the Google Search Console

Falconridge Oil, *Unity Developer*, Toronto, Ontario

Feb. 2018 - Mar. 2018

- Created 3D animations for investor focused videos using Blender to demonstrate various aspects of the company's main product
- Created interactive versions of scenes from the promotional videos using Unity3d, programming the version in C#

Computer Adventure Camp, Owner, Tainan, Taiwan

2017

- Designed, created, and ran a computer literacy and programming course for children about to enter an experimental programming class in the upcoming school year.
- Designed the camp's textbook and curriculum based off of the Hour of Code materials.

Tainan Bilingual International Education Association, *English Teacher*, 2015 - Tainan, Taiwan 2017

- Was the school's founding English teacher
- Created the school's English curriculum based off of the American Common Core standards
- Helped train new teachers in how to manage classrooms and teach the school's demanding curriculum.

ESL Teacher and Writer, *Teacher and writer*, Taipei, Taiwan

2006 - 2014

- Held positions at different private ESL schools, mainly teaching young children, kindergarten to grade 2, and advanced adults
- Tutor university students, teaching test prep and academic English.
- Wrote for *Time for Students,* an ESL news magazine, as well as *Yuan*, a magazine put out by the Taiwan Research Institute.

Bank of Montreal, Network and Desktop Support, Toronto, Canada 1999 - 2002

- Worked with the NT4 team doing second level network and desktop support.
- Provided desktop and network support for executives and the board of directors.
- Queue manager, in charge of tracking and assigning support tickets to members of various teams.

EDUCATION

Lighthouse Labs 2018
Cheng Kung University Language Center 2014
York University 2006

B.A., English Language and Literature